Pavel Gordon

Senior Software Engineer

0157 39480 298

gordon.pav@gmail.com

ttps://pgordon.dev

Hamburg



I am a backend (Java/Kotlin) software engineer with 4+ years of professional experience and passion for clean and performant code. I build distributed, robust and fault-tolerant services for businesses.

I always push myself to be a better developer and stay up to date with the latest technology trends.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Software Engineer

FreeNOW | Jul 2018 - Present

Developed reliable, highly available and scalable low latency services for the ride-hailing system. As a part of an allocation team, I was responsible for maintaining and improving dispatching logic

- reducing waiting time for passengers, optimizing the distribution of tours for drivers.

Participated in architectural decisions between the teams, investigated and processed production incidents.

Constantly improved tech stack and exchanged knowledge within the tribe.

Technologies: Java 11/Kotlin, Spring, Postgres, Git, RabbitMQ, AWS/Kubernetes, Scrum/Kanban

Software Engineer

Interra LLC | Jul 2017 - Feb 2018

Developed multiple projects for local government:

- SaaS platform for online education in Russian schools. My key tech challenges were to migrate the existing platform to Spring Boot and split monolithic architecture to microservices.
- SCADA system for monitoring railway traffic in Saint-Petersburg. As a core developer, I was responsible for the architectural and tech choices of this project, creating workflow and a system from scratch.

Technologies: Java, Spring, Postgres, Git, Angular 4, Typescript, Kanban

Java Developer

T-Systems RUS | Feb 2016 - Jul 2017

Developed internal projects (time-tracking and absence management system, in-office navigation platform)

Maintained and improved disaster handling system for replacing failed network communication nodes.

Developed a testing toolkit for mocking web-services of Deutsche Telekom.

Technologies: Java, MySQL, Ruby on Rails, CoffeeScript, Oracle, PL/SQL, Scrum

ACTIVITY

I participate at hackathons, visit various IT conferences (e.g. KotlinKonf) across the globe.

Winner at Junction'17 Helsinki

Winner at AngelHack'15 Moscow

SKILLS

Technical

Java/Kotlin

Spring, JPA (Hibernate)

PostgreSQL, MySQL, Mongo

Maven/Gradle

Microservices

Tools

OS X, IntelliJ, Git

Agile (Scrum, Kanban)

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Science

ITMO University Saint-Petersburg 2013 - 2017

LANGUAGES

English (Professional)

Russian (Native)

German (Elementary)

I INTERESTS

Travelling

Smart Home

Tech